Guide to the Press of the Woolly Whale Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Press of the Woolly Whale records
1893-1968
1928-1941
GEN MSS 932
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
19.4
(53 boxes) + 5 broadside folders
The collection primarily consists of correspondence and production files related to publications issued by the Press of the Woolly Whale, including original and carbon typescripts, corrected page proofs and galleys, paper samples, title page and endpaper designs, dummies, notes, and receipts. Some of the production files hold original artwork for illustrations; also present are four photoengravings used to print endpapers for Melbert B. Cary's two-volume work Mademoiselle from Armentieres. In addition, the records contain the press's archival set of Woolly Whale publications including ephemeral items such as prospectuses, invitations, broadsides, holiday cards, mailing labels, and certificates, as well as four chronologically arranged scrapbooks created by Cary to hold samples of ephemera, reviews of the press's work, and other clippings. For his productions Cary employed favorite artists such as Alban B. Butler, Warren Chappell, W. A. Dwiggins, Willi Harweth, Fritz Kredel, and Philip G. Reed, and authors including Richard Le Gallienne; several of the volumes in the press copies set have bespoke bindings by prominent hand binders Katharine Adams, Douglas Cockerell & Son, Peter Franck, Otto Fratzscher, and Gerhard Gerlach. Other correspondents in the collection include Paul and Rudolf Koch, Robert Winslow Gordon, and firms such as Gebrüder Klingspor.
Press of the Woolly Whale
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 58: Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Mary Flagler Cary Charitable Trust, 1969.
Associated Materials
The Melbert B. Cary Graphic Arts Collection at Rochester Institute of Technology holds additional Press of the Woolly Whale records including production files (CSC 023) and the press's visitor register (CSC 022).
Press of the Woolly Whale
The Press of the Woolly Whale was in operation in New York City from 1928 to 1942, during which time it produced private and limited edition volumes, publications related to printing and typographic arts, and a wide variety of ephemera that reflected the interests, professional relationships, and personal humor of Melbert Brinkerhoff Cary Jr., his wife Mary Flagler Cary, and their friends. While Cary directed the press's efforts, he employed George W. Van Vechten Jr. for typesetting and press work. Two exhibitions profiled the press's achievements (Grosvenor Library, Buffalo, New York, in 1939, and Rochester Institute of Technology in 1972); the catalogs from those exhibitions contained bibliographies which were superseded by David Pankow's checklist in Melbert B. Cary, Jr. and the Press of the Woolly Whale (Rochester: Cary Graphic Arts Press, Rochester Institute of Technology, 2002).
Melbert B. Cary Jr. and Mary Flagler Cary
Melbert Brinkerhoff Cary Jr. (1892-1941), a New York businessman and prominent figure in the fields of typography and private printing during the second quarter of the twentieth century, was born in New York, the son of Melbert and Julia Metcalf Cary. Educated at the Groton School and Yale University (Class of 1916), he served in France with the American Expeditionary Forces during World War I. Cary was the director of the Continental Typefounders Association, Inc., which he organized in New York City in 1925 to import from Europe the best new designs in type, initials, borders, and ornaments being developed by foundries on the continent, but cast to American type height and using the American point system so that designers and printers in the United States could use fresh and modern faces for commercial advertising.
In 1923 Cary married Mary Harkness Flagler (1901-1967), the daughter of Anne Lamont and Harry Harkness Flagler, and the granddaughter of Henry Morrison Flagler, one of the founders of the Standard Oil Company. She was raised in New York City and in Millbrook, New York, where the Carys continued to maintain homes after their marriage. Melbert Cary Jr. served as president of the American Institute of Graphic Arts, was proprietor of the private Press of the Woolly Whale, and a collector of printer's manuals and type specimens, great books of the printer's art, and rare playing cards; he acquired the Kelmscott/Goudy Press (Albion No. 6551) on which William Morris had printed The Works of Geoffrey Chauce r (1896), from Frederic W. Goudy in 1932. Mary Flagler Cary was the president of the National Orchestral Association and a collector of rare manuscript music.
George W. Van Vechten Jr.
George W. Van Vechten Jr., American printer, typographer, and book designer, was born in New Brunswick, New Jersey, attended Carnegie Institute of Technology, and died in Metuchen, New Jersey, in 1962, at age 55. He produced private and limited edition works for thirty-five years with Frederic W. Goudy at the Village Press, with Melbert B. Cary Jr. at the Press of the Woolly Whale, and from 1941 to 1962 at his own Van Vechten Press in Metuchen. Van Vechten inherited the Kelmscott/Goudy Press (Albion No. 6551) upon Cary's death in 1941.
Scope and Contents
The records primarily consist of correspondence and production files related to work created at the Press of the Woolly Whale, including original and carbon typescripts, corrected page proofs and galleys, paper samples, title page and endpaper designs, dummies, notes, and receipts. Some of the production files hold original artwork for illustrations; also present are four photoengravings used to print endpapers for Melbert B. Cary's two-volume work Mademoiselle from Armentieres. In addition, the records contain the press's archival set of Woolly Whale publications including ephemeral items such as prospectuses, invitations, broadsides, holiday cards, mailing labels, and certificates, as well as four chronologically arranged scrapbooks created by Cary to hold samples of small ephemera, reviews of the press's work, and other related clippings. Many of the Woolly Whale publications were produced as holiday, anniversary, and birthday greetings, and tributes to respected colleagues, particularly Frederic W. Goudy. A military veteran, Cary issued annual tributes to Armistice Day beginning in 1928 ranging in format from a simple broadside to a set of playing cards, The Devil's Bible.
For his productions Cary employed favorite artists such as Alban B. Butler, Warren Chappell, W. A. Dwiggins, Willi Harwerth, Fritz Kredel, and Philip G. Reed, and authors including Richard Le Gallienne; several of the volumes in the press copies set have bespoke bindings by prominent hand binders Katharine Adams, Douglas Cockerell & Son, Peter Franck, Otto Fratzscher, and Gerhard Gerlach. Other correspondents in the collection include Paul and Rudolf Koch, Robert Winslow Gordon, and firms such as Gebrüder Klingspor.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Correspondence and Papers, 1893-1968. II. Scrapbooks, 1928-1942. III. Production Files, 1928-1942. IV. Press of the Woolly Whale Publications, 1928-1942.
Graphic arts -- United States; Illustration of books -- 20th Century; Letterpress printing -- United States; Printers -- New York (State) -- New York; Private presses -- New York (State) -- New York; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York; Announcements -- United States -- 20th Century; Broadsheet (format) -- United States -- 20th Century; Ephemera (general object genre) -- United States -- 20th Century; Greeting cards -- United States -- 20th Century; Invitations -- United States -- 20th Century; Mechanicals (camera-ready copy) -- United States -- 20th Century; Mock-ups -- United States -- 20th Century; Printing plates -- United States -- 20th Century; Proofs (prints by function) -- United States -- 20th Century; Prospectuses -- United States -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Printers -- New York (State) -- New York -- 20th Century; Adams, Katharine, 1862-1952; Butler, Alban B., Jr., 1891-1949; Cary, Mary Flagler, 1901-1967; Cary, Melbert B., Jr., 1892-1941; Chappell, Warren, 1904-1991; Dwiggins, W. A. (William Addison), 1880-1956; Emmons, Earl H., 1888-1949; Franck, Peter; Fratzscher, Otto; Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942; Gerlach, Gerhard, 1907-1968; Gordon, Robert Winslow; Goudy, Frederic W. (Frederic William), 1865-1947; Harwerth, Willi, 1894-1982; Hosking, Arthur Nicholas, 1874-1970; Kleukens, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1878-1956; Koch, Paul, 1906-1945; Koch, Rudolf, 1876-1934; Kredel, Fritz, 1900-1973; Le Gallienne, Richard, 1866-1947; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974; Reed, Philip G.; Ruppel, Aloys, 1882-1977; Saxl, Fritz, 1890-1948; Van Vechten, George W., -1922; Wang, Chi-Chen, 1899-2001; American Institute of Graphic Arts; Douglas Cockerell & Son (Firm); Gebrüder Klingspor; Press of the Woolly Whale; Reynolds Metals Company
- Correspondence and Papers, 1893-1968; Series I; 0.84; (2 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into four subseries: Melbert B. Cary Papers, Mary Flagler Cary Papers, Inventories, and Other Papers.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains general correspondence files regarding the press and printing, and a group of publications stock inventories made after Melbert Cary's death. Also filed here are original designs considered for the Woolly Whale pressmark. Other Papers contains publications found with the Woolly Whale records but not produced by the press, including copies of the catalogue from the first exhibition of the press's work. Correspondence related to specific publications and other press projects is in Series III, Production Files.
  - Melbert B. Cary Papers
    Arranged under two headings: Correspondence, and Subject Files
    - Correspondence
      - Bausch and Lomb Optical Company, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Cards of Wood, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Dwiggins, W. A. (William Addison), 1936-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Gebrüder Klingspor, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Gollifox Press, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Harwerth, Willi, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Hosking, Arthur Nicholas, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Kleukens, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Koch, Paul, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Koch, Rudolf, 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
      - Le Gallienne, Richard, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Lee, Robert E., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Reynolds Metals Company, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Ruppel, Aloys, 1940-1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Saxl, Fritz, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Wolpe, Berthold, 1933-1934 (Box 51 (Oversize), Folder 17)
      - General correspondence, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Subject Files
      - American private presses and printers, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Notes, miscellaneous, 1934, 1937. undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Pressmark designs, 1929, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21-24)
      - Tudor houses, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Mary Flagler Cary Papers
    - General correspondence, 1938-1959 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Copyright inquiries, 1942-1959 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Kelmscott/Goudy Press history, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - George Van Vechten obituaries, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Inventories
    - Paper and type, 1936, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Press stock and sales records, 1941-1959 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Other Papers
    - American Institute of Graphic Arts, The Village Press: A Retrospective Exhibition (exhibition catalogue), 1933 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Artzybasheff, Boris, Let George Do It! (Typophiles Keepsake 68), 1941 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Flagler, Harry Harkness, The Story of a Dream as it was told to the friends of Mr. Walpole at the Club of Odd Volumes [Charles River, MA: Sign of the George]; designed by Bruce Rogers, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Flagler Memorial Chapel of Millbrook School; designed by Bruce Rogers, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - The Gettysburg Address, XIX November, MDCCCLXIII (Philadelphia: Lanston Monotype Machine Company), undated (Box 53 (Broadside), Folder 36)
    - Grosvenor Library, Buffalo, New York, The Press of the Woolly Whale (exhibition catalogue, 3 copies), 1939 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Philobiblon issues 1 and 3, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - William Morris Society, The Typographical Adventure of William Morris (exhibition catalogue), 1957 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - German ephemera, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1893-1968 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Scrapbooks, 1928-1942; Series II; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Series II is arranged chronologically.
  The series contains four volumes of scrapbooks, specially bound in stamped calf and enclosed in titled slipcases, that were created to hold material by and about the Press of the Woolly Whale. Each contains samples of printed ephemera produced by the press such as stationery, invitations, luggage tags, mailing labels, postcards, and pamphlets, as well as clippings from newspapers and trade journals regarding publications of the press. A fifth scrapbook had a detached spine and front cover, and no slipcase; the material within had only been laid in between the first few pages in the front of the volume so it was removed and foldered, and the scrapbook discarded. Additional copies of material found in the scrapbooks may also appear in Series IV, Press of the Woolly Whale Publications.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1928-1933 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1934-1936 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1937-1938 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Production Files, 1928-1942; Series III; 7.72; (23 boxes) + 2 broadside folders
  Series III is arranged chronologically.
  The series contains files related to the production of publications issued by the press, including correspondence, notes, original artwork, paper samples, dummies, mechanicals, and proofs. As the projects were primarily of Cary's own creation few of the files contain correspondence, but there are exceptions. Two such publications are (41) Mademoiselle from Armentieres, vol. II, and (47) Estivation of Two Mao Tzu which both have correspondence and research materials. The first contains versions of the songs Cary collected from veterans and others, correspondence with Robert Winslow Gordon of the Library of Congress Music Division's Archive of Folk Song, and an article Cary published in the Journal of American Folklore 47 (1934); the second has correspondence with scholar Chi-Chen Wang and with Carroll T. Harris, Cary's typesetter for the book. Many of the files hold original drawings used for illustrations, particularly the work of Alban Butler Jr., and the files for (37) Some Thoughts on the Ornamented Mss. of the Middle Ages contain multiple photographs by Arnold Genthe of the Kelmscott/Goudy Press (Albion No. 6551) plus Warren Chappell's drawing after one of those images.
  The projects are arranged by the checklist number established in David Pankow's annotated bibliography Melbert B. Cary, Jr. and the Press of the Woolly Whale (2002), which is arranged chronologically. There is not a file for every project; numbers in brackets indicate the items that do not appear in the bibliography. Filed at the end of the series is work accomplished for organizations with which the Carys were closely involved, projects contemplated but not completed, and unidentified artwork.
  - 1. Le Chapeau Immortel, by Earl H. Emmons, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - 1. Le Chapeau Immortel, by Earl H. Emmons, 1928 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 44)
  - 2. Ici Vaincu, 1928 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 45)
  - 3. A Poem Written on the Occasion of the Wooden Wedding Anniversary of Mary & Melbert Cary Jr., 1928 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - [3a.] An Ode to B. Franklin, Printer, by Earl H. Emmons, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    General note
    Insert for The American Printer (January 1929)
  - 4. The Vision of Sir Launfal, by James Russell Lowell, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 48-49)
  - 5. War, by Richard Le Gallienne, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - [5a.] Companionship of Stars, by Julia Metcalf Cary, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - 8. The Press of the Woolly Whale. Anyone who is fortunate..., 1928 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - 9. A Christmas Carol in Prose: Being a Ghost Story of Christmas, by Charles Dickens, 1930 (Box 8 (Oversize), Folder 53-54)
  - 10. Mademoiselle from Armentieres, vol. I, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 55-59)
  - 10. Mademoiselle from Armentieres, vol. I: photoengravings for endpapers, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 60-61)
  - 14. Julia M. Cary, 1856-1930, by John Haynes Holmes, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 62-63)
  - 14. Julia M. Cary, 1856-1930, by John Haynes Holmes, 1931 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 64)
  - 15. Molly Make Believe, by Eleanor Hallowell Abbott, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 65-66)
  - 16. And It Came to Pass [St. Luke, chapter 2], 1931 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - 17. Knowledge and Faith, by Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - 17. Knowledge and Faith, by Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, 1932 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 69)
  - 18. Terms of the Armistice, 1930-1932 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - 18. Terms of the Armistice, 1932 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 71)
  - 19. Poverty and Plenty, by Walter Lippmann, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - 21. The Sentimental Bloke, by C. J. Dennis, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - 22. A Modern Version of the Night Before Christmas, by Robert McBlair, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - [23a.] Epicede, by Algernon Charles Swinburne, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - 24. The Story of the Village Type, by Frederic W Goudy, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 76-78)
  - 25. Digressions for the Traveller in England, by Melbert B. Cary Jr., 1933 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 79)
  - 26. Patriotism versus Welfare: An Extract from "The Unseen Assassins", by Norman Angell, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 80-81)
  - 27. Devil's Bible, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - 27. Devil's Bible, 1933 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 83-84)
  - 27. Devil's Bible, 1933 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 85-86)
  - 27. Devil's Bible, 1933 (Box 57 (Broadside), Folder 433)
  - 28. Stille Nacht, Heilige Nacht: A Christmas Song, by Franz Gruber, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 87-88)
  - 28. Stille Nacht, Heilige Nacht: A Christmas Song, by Franz Gruber, 1933 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 89)
  - 29. The Palingenesis of Craps, by Edward Larocque Tinker, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 90-93)
  - 29. The Palingenesis of Craps, by Edward Larocque Tinker, 1933 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 94)
  - 30. Bank Holiday Luncheon. Stowaways, March 8, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - 32. Quinquennalia, 1928-1933; Fifth Birthday Party, Woolly Whale. (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - 37. Some Thoughts on the Ornamented Mss. of the Middle Ages, by William Morris, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 97-101)
  - 37. Some Thoughts on the Ornamented Mss. of the Middle Ages, by William Morris, 1934 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 102)
  - 38. Design and Beauty in Printing, by Frederic W Goudy, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 103-104)
  - 40. An Extract from The Enemies of Books, by William Blades, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 105-108)
  - 40. An Extract from The Enemies of Books, by William Blades, 1934 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 109)
  - 41. Mademoiselle from Armentieres, vol. II, 1931-1935 (Box 14, Folder 110-118)
  - 41. Mademoiselle from Armentieres, vol. II, 1931-1935 (Box 15, Folder 119-121)
  - 41. Mademoiselle from Armentieres, vol. II: photoengravings for endpapers, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 122-123)
  - 41. Mademoiselle from Armentieres, vol. II, 1931-1935 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 124-125)
  - 42. Warmest Greetings to Walter J. Damrosch, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 126)
  - 47. Estivation of Two Mao Tzu, by Melbert B. Cary, Jr., 1935 (Box 17, Folder 127-132)
  - 47. Estivation of Two Mao Tzu, by Melbert B. Cary Jr., 1935 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 133-136)
  - 47. Estivation of Two Mao Tzu, by Melbert B. Cary, Jr., 1935 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 137)
  - 52. Jonah and the Woolly Whale Were Breakfasting, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 138)
  - 53. Merry Christmas from Two Mao Tzu, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 139)
  - 54. Exaggerated Nationalism, by Richard Le Gallienne, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 140)
  - 55. Some New Light on the Genesis of the Ampersand, [by Melbert B. Cary, Jr.], 1936 (Box 17, Folder 141)
  - 57. The Ninth Man, by Mary Heaton Vorse, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 142-148)
  - 57. The Ninth Man, by Mary Heaton Vorse, 1936 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 149)
  - 58. The Treasure in the Forest, by H. G. Wells, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 150-154)
  - 58. The Treasure in the Forest, by H. G. Wells, 1936 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 155)
  - 59. Announcing a Typographic Divertissement by Mwano Masassi, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 156)
  - 60. Americanism: What Is It?, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 157)
  - 61. William Henry Metcalf: A Biography by his Daughter, by Julia Metcalf Cary, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 158-160)
  - 61. William Henry Metcalf: A Biography by his Daughter, by Julia Metcalf Cary, 1937 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 161)
  - 63. War Cards: A Prolusion, by Melbert B. Cary, Jr., 1937 (Box 20, Folder 162-167)
  - 63. War Cards: A Prolusion, by Melbert B. Cary Jr., 1937 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 168)
  - 64. Index to War Cards, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 169)
  - 67. May Meeting, 1937, The Club of Odd Volumes (Box 20, Folder 170)
  - 68. Press of the Woolly Whale, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 171)
  - 70. Devices from [& by] Many Typophiles, by Paul Bennett, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 172)
  - 72. A Bibliography of the Village Press, 1903-1938, by Melbert B. Cary Jr. (Box 21, Folder 173-174)
  - 73. A Prayer for a Wedding, by John Haynes Holmes, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 175-176)
  - 73. A Prayer for a Wedding, by John Haynes Holmes, 1938 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 177)
  - 74. Schnitzelbank; Metamorphosed from the Original German with Sketches by Fritz Kredel, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 178-179)
  - 74. Schnitzelbank; Metamorphosed from the Original German with Sketches by Fritz Kredel, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 180)
  - 77. Addenda to A Bibliography of the Village Press, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 181)
  - 82. The Savor of the Feast (Typophiles dinner for Fritz and Annie Kredel), 1938 (Box 22, Folder 182-183)
  - 83. Progressive Layouts for "On Dry-Cow Fishing," as Designed by Bruce Rogers, by Bruce Rogers, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 184)
  - 83. Progressive Layouts for "On Dry-Cow Fishing," as Designed by Bruce Rogers, 1938 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 185)
  - 86. My Little Dachshund; A Doggerel and Madrigal by an Old Elizabethan Composer of the XXth Century, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 186-187)
  - 86. My Little Dachshund; A Doggerel and Madrigal by an Old Elizabethan Composer of the XXth Century, 1939 (Box 28 (Oversize), Folder 188)
  - 87. The Black Art, by D. B. Updike, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 189)
  - 87. The Black Art, by D. B. Updike, 1939 (Box 28 (Oversize), Folder 190)
  - 90. Rules of the Library; Made in the Second Year of Richard III ... November 3, 1484, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 191)
  - 90. Rules of the Library; Made in the Second Year of Richard III ... November 3, 1484, 1939 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 192)
  - 92. To the Members of the Institute; invitation to 25th anniversary meeting, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 193)
  - 93. The Work of Bruce Rogers; Jack of All Trades, Master of One; subscription notice and order slip, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 194)
  - [95a.] American Institute of Graphic Arts, Henry Watson Kent dinner, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 195)
  - 96. Gutenberg and the Strasbourg Documents of 1439, by Otto W. Fuhrmann, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 196)
  - 97. The World Must Federate! Isolation versus Cooperation, by Hans Kahn, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 197)
  - 98. The Missing Gutenberg Wooden Blocks, by Melbert B. Cary Jr., 1940 (Box 23, Folder 198)
  - 98. The Missing Gutenberg Wooden Blocks, by Melbert B. Cary Jr., 1940 (Box 29 (Oversize), Folder 199)